Hello and welcome. In this session, we
will look at the
demos about new capabilities, very very
new capabilities in the supply chain
area.
What we will see today, subcontracting.
Yeah, majority of subcontracting was
added in minor release, but we added
something in
this release as well.
For more subcontracting details, we will
see the full session and you can find
link in the description.
We also have have enhancements in
manufacturing related to planning
worksheet on how we create release
production orders from there. A lot of
usability enhancements.
Also,
transfer orders, they got extra
capabilities as well and alignment
between different modes.
Plus,
number of improvements in the quality
management.
Let's start looking at the demos.
Subcontracting first.
As I mentioned, the full overview of
subcontracting capabilities is a
separate one. Here about like very very
new.
I have released production order
and I navigate to routings
and from routings, I will navigate to
already created purchase order because I
did it up front.
What do we see here?
We see here
purchase document,
bulk assembly. First of all, a lot of
changes in demo data, so now we have
more information to support different
subcontracting scenarios.
But,
now to the lines. We can see there are
multiple lines
and these three are something new. So,
this is additional comments which we
provide to supplier
to instruct them on what to do in this
specific operation. Assemble housing,
perform visual inspection
and or refer to attached document. So,
apparently we're also attaching some
document. Where is it? It's attached to
this line and we navigate to line
attachments.
Right here.
So, there is attachment.
Where this information is coming from is
coming from
from routing.
You can navigate to operations and see
subcontracting comment.
And you can see attachment and if you
choose the show details,
you can see that it flows to production
order and to purchase document as well.
Both are enabled, that's why we got
attachment in the purchase document.
All right. So, now our
supplier is fully equipped with the
information on what to do is and how to
perform the operation.
Now, operation is done. We are getting
our
product back.
And how we handle it? Now, we can
actually handle it with uh
inventory put-aways as well in addition
to normal posting and warehouse
receipts.
But before we doing that, let's take a
look at the item tracking lines. I
already defined two out of three.
Uh and now I will create
It's not required, but I just want to
demonstrate you how it flows
between uh between documents and choose
create inventory put-away.
Okay?
Put-away created. Now,
related
inventory put-away and pick lines and
show document.
All right. So, my put-away document is
created and for each line I got separate
lines like two serial numbers I
specified up front. Now, I will add one
more.
Auto fill quantity to handle because I
need to put ones everywhere and post it.
Post receipt.
All right.
So, operation is completed. I received
the item and if I will jump back to my
production order
and scroll to the right, I can see that
finished quantity is three. Inventory
put away supports
last operation and non-last operation as
well. But in this case, you cannot
specify serial numbers.
All right. So, these are two
subcontracting specific enhancements.
Let's take a look at the next three
demos in one go. Let's start with the
planning planning worksheet.
All right. I will search for my planning
worksheet.
Apparently, it was already here. I have
two lines already created
with item.
And what do I do next? Different
quantity. I will choose carry out action
message.
And now in production orders in the
in this list, I can select two extra
options. I can create production orders
in status released
or released and print. Let's make the
complex part released and print and
choose okay.
Can you see? Posting automatic
consumption. Yeah, so this specific item
config uses flushing both for components
and for routings. Before jumping, let's
take a look at the
document which was printed meanwhile.
Yeah, production order company and
routing lines for the first and for the
second order. And if you can look a
closer
closer closer closer
at this screw, the remaining quantity is
zero. Why? Because operation these ones
were
automatically consumed when production
order of status released was created.
All right.
Let's navigate to production orders.
Released.
And we can see these two in the in the
very bottom
auto drip which we added. So, let's take
a look at the the latest one
and take a look at the
entries.
Item ledger entries.
And you can see consumption of what?
Screw hex.
Exactly.
Plenty of them. And what about uh
what about uh capacity?
And one of operations like the body
assembly was also performed
automatically, yeah? Because it's also
using flushing method in reality.
All right. That's good. So, now we can
create release production orders, but
again, just want to demonstrate if you
have a flushing backwards backward uh
forward flushing uh method with a no
routing links, be careful.
Posting will happen automatically.
All right.
What else do we have here?
We have another
production order I prepared up front,
and now I choose refresh production
order because it has no lines. Yeah, let
me calculate it now.
And I get the error.
Actionable error, not just error.
Uh which tells me that status is
actually
not certified in my routing. And I can
jump directly to my routing
and uh certified change status to
certified. But before I do that, let me
change type from serial to parallel.
Look at the lines.
I got uh previous and next operations
visible automatically.
Now, back to serial. They're not
visible. We added the dynamic
visibility, so if you are working, and
some people do, with uh
uh parallel
routings, the fields will become visible
automatically without need for you to do
any personalization.
All right. What else do I want to tell?
Let's take a look at this machine
center.
I will
use my favorite client feature, show
detail.
Love it.
All right, I'm navigating to machine
center card and I'm scrolling down and I
can see the new field, which is
dangerously red. It says calendar
entries available until
What does it mean? Apparently, I don't
have any calendar entries. I have like
only one
on day on year 2025.
Not good. Now it's a year 2026. Better
to have a little bit more data. How can
I fix it?
I can choose calculate machine center
calendar right from here. So, we just
added this report to machine center card
as well. It's a pre-filtered
and starting date, yeah, current uh
work year, which is acceptable
for this demo. And now it is not red,
but normal normal text.
So, that's another usability uh
improvement.
Next ones.
Now we will be talking about direct
transfers. Yeah, we can move components
or finished good or raw material
or retail goods from one location to
another in three different ways. We can
use the
uh
ship and receipt posting shipment and
receipt separately or you can use two
modes of direct transfers.
Direct
and ship and receipt. Let's start by
searching list of transfer orders.
Transfer orders. We have a pretty good
article in the documentation explaining
differences between all of these three
methods
and what what is happening.
All right.
Let me open this transfer order, which
is moving goods from the very advanced
white location, which requires directed
put-away and pick, to normal main
location. And it is using logistic. So,
I can post
ship separately, receipt separately. I
can modify quantities, etc. But what if
I will choose direct transfer? Now,
I can activate it on the transfer order,
that's not new, but now I have ability
to decide
about the mode on how exactly my direct
transfer will be posted. Is it one go
and document posted one-to-one, no
modifications allowed, but some some
warehouse handling is allowed here, or
do I want to create separate shipment
and receipt documents?
It used to be not possible to do what
I'm doing right now. Select shipment and
receipt. You just could not do that like
in the previous release
because we were blocking this this one.
But now it is
it is working. I create my warehouse
shipment. I need to create a pick. I
will get some items selected. Where is
my pick lines?
Apparently, I have a lot. This
item was distributed in many different
across many different bins.
Uh
register pick.
All good. Back to my shipment. Now I can
ship. Do I want to ship all 10?
Actually, not. I want to ship only six.
And this is a benefit of direct transfer
of mode ship and receipt. It supports
partial shipping.
Now it also supports
if from location requires warehouse
shipment.
Okay.
But uh
wait, there is more.
If I navigate to if I close this
transfer order
and go to related warehouse and transfer
route, which are also available through
the search, I can do something with
transfer routes. So, I want to move
something from
yellow location
to main location.
And when I do that, I want it to happen
automatically, direct transfer.
This field you can see also these two
fields are now available in the on the
transfer route specification.
And I can change it and decide to use
shipment and receipt.
By default, the values coming here is
from inventory posting setup as before,
but yeah, you can override it on for
specific route
or you can later modify it for specific
transfer document as well.
All right.
Close.
From yellow
to
main location.
And you can see activated automatically
shipment and receipt
already populated.
But wait, I can also now define in
transit location code
and use
transit location. So now when I will
post my transfer document as a ship and
receive,
I will not be using item ledger entries
with a blank location code. So finally,
we can remove
these lines from the inventory posting
setup because they are not needed for
transfers and they are not needed
anymore from previous since previous
release
in manufacturing.
Let me remind you that we have a
manufacturing setup.
And we have copy location code in to
value entry links to capacity ledger
entry. Very long
description of the field, but it's very
valuable. So now
location code will be always populated
into in the value entries like
related to manufacturing.
So
empty inventory posting setup like
inventory posting setup entries with a
empty location
not needed anymore.
Which is a good news.
All right. What do we want to do next?
We want to explore this
location. You can see that I configured
it to require put away and pick only.
So, inventory put away and pick. And
what do I do? I specify quantity.
And I choose create inventory pick.
Inventory pick created. Navigate to this
inventory pick.
Quantity to handle. Again, let's
demonstrate that we can do the partial
shipment and post
inventory pick for outbound transfer and
inbound transfer simultaneously. There
goes the confirmation dialog. Posted.
Let's close it for now.
Let's close it for now. And you can see
that I indeed moved uh
three out of four to my main location
using inventory pick. So, you don't need
to use all of these methods all
together, but you decide which one works
better for you. These direct transfers
are very convenient when you need to
register transfer to some remote
location where you're not in control.
You don't have any warehouse handling
procedures.
For example, if you're moving something
to
subcontractor. Yeah? Then, you probably
would like to prefer direct transfer,
but it doesn't mean you cannot use more
advanced locations
as a as a from location. As a source
location from which you are sending
goods. And I do all now dramatically
less restricted on which posting method
to use.
Because you can see shipment and receipt
has its own benefits comparing to direct
transfer.
All right. Next topic, quality
inspection. Quality inspection separate
up installed available used by many and
we did number of limited number, but
of enhancements here.
And let's back to the demonstrations.
I'm still in my transfer order list
because I decided to do something
different this time and try to post
transfer order. Post transfer order.
All right.
What does it tells me? That it's blocked
by quantity inspection. Yeah? So,
transfer is not allowed for this item
with item tracking because quality
inspection
has a result fail.
All right. Show quality inspection.
I can navigate to my quality inspection
and see it is indeed fail
because
something
with a defect types did not went as
expected. All right. Now I go to the all
details.
Let's imagine that now I have a
different role and I need to do the
re-inspection. Let me create a new
inspection for this one.
I can do that? Yes.
All right. Let me change the sample size
to be something different this time. It
will be 20.
You can see as soon as I modified
something in the header, I got the
notification recommending me to assign
this inspection to myself. Yeah, I can
choose it and now user is is me. Makes
sense because if I'm working with
inspection, makes sense to allocate it
to myself.
By the way, not all fields can be
modified by normal user.
Sometimes you need to have
quality admin or supervisor role.
Quality inspection apps provide like
number of roles for
person who is doing inspection, for
administrator who can modify number of
fields, for example, assign user and
assign it to somebody else, not himself
or themself, but somebody else, but also
modify the different quantity fields
like sample size or failed or passed
quantity. So, that's user
administrator is responsible for. Also,
administrator can reopen inspection or
delete finished inspections. Otherwise,
they these actions are blocked.
All right. Let's go and enter some
information. Package visual, undamaged.
Label is correct.
Uh all is form is good.
Content is like fine. No comments.
Everything passed. And now I'm finishing
inspection.
Do you want to change it? Yeah, finish.
Notice that now after I finish
inspection, my sample size was moved to
the past quantity because inspection
passed. So, past quantity is updated
automatically. Previously, because my
previous inspection failed,
the failed quantity was initialized.
And these values can be used in the
workflows.
That's it about quality inspection.
Let's have a look. Did I demonstrate uh
everything which I plan to do plan to
do? Yes, exactly. So, new
subcontracting, a lot of manufacturing
improvements
in addition to subcontracting, direct
transfer orders, and quality
inspections.
Thank you.